Guide to the Morris Schappes Papers TAM.179
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1911-2004
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 13. (III), 1952-1978 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 13. "Cold War 1940s", 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 14. "Postlude: Past the Mid-Century" (I), 1963-1976 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 14. (II), 1963-1976 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - A Pictorial History...: Supplement (1954-1965) from Revised Edition (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - A Pictorial History...: Clippings, including Reviews, and Advertisements, 1959, 1965-1968 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - A Pictorial History...: Correspondence, 1966-1984 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - A Pictorial History...: Royalty Statements, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Platt, David, 1986-1991 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Poale Zion: Clippings, 1945-1956 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Poale Zion: Research Notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Poland: Religious Freedom, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Polatnick, Melvin, 1996-1999 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Political Correctness, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - "Political Origins of the United Hebrew Trades": Correspondence, 1948-1955 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Porter, Jack Nusan, 1970, 1991-1995 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Porter, Jack Nusan, 1985-2000 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Prago, Albert, 1981-1994 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Price-Fixing: Kosher Products, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Proskauer, Joseph M., 1950-1971 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Protestant Establishment, 1964-1980 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Psychiatry and History, 1966, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Publications: Jewish Marine League Pamphlet, [1939] (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Publications: Jewish Periodicals - Various, 1986, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Publications: Jews in America, 1945-1974 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Publications: The Jews in Nazi Germany - The Factual Record of their Persecution by the National Socialists, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Publications: National Research League Bulletin February 1935 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Publications: Newsletters, Press Releases, Announcements and Reports - Various, 1957-2002 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Publications: Post-War Israel-Palestine Issues, 1946-1956, 1975-1986 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Publications: Various, 1948-1986, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Publications: Various, 1969-1978 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Publications: Various, 1981-2002 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Publications: Various - Yiddish, 1933-1955, 1967, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Puffin Foundation, 1992-2001 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Puffin Foundation: Brochures, 1992-1999 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Pushkin, 1959, 1971-1983 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Racist Humor, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Rappoport, Joseph, 1980-1981 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Reagan Administration, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Reconstructionism, 1981, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Red Scare / McCarthyism, 1945-1998 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Reisman, Philip, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Reproductive Rights, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Resnick, Sid, 1985-1997 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Restrictive Covenants: Supreme Court Rulings Shelley v. Kraemer and Muro v. Hodge, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Retail Drug Employees Union, Local 1199, 1957 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Reverse Discrimination, 1974-1975 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - The Rise of David Levinsky, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Robeson, Paul, 1970, 1987, 1997-1999 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Robeson, Paul, Jr., 1989-1997 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Romani (Gypsies), 1984-1991 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Romani (Gypsies), 1992-1995, undated (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Romania, 1951, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.: Attitude toward Jews, 1979-1982 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.: New Deal, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Rose, Ernestine Louise: Research - Biographical Articles and Dramatizations, 1943-1949, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Rose, Ernestine Louise: Research - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Rose, Ernestine Louise: Research - Correspondence, 1947-1950, 1974-1976 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Rose, Ernestine Louise: Research - Document Copies and Transcriptions (1850-1892), 1947, 1949, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Rose, Ernestine Louise: Research - Notes, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel: Case, 1951-1954, 1974-1979 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel: Case, 1980-1988 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel: Case, 1990-1996 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel: Case - "The Kaufman Papers", 1951-1975 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Rosenbergs: Commemorations, 1953-1954, 1965, 1986-1988 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Rosenbergs: Film Daniel, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Rosenbergs: Invitation to an Inquest and The Rosenberg File, [1965], 1983 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Rosenbergs: Invitation to an Inquest and The Rosenberg File, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Rosenfield, Max, 1957-1999 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Roth, Philip, 1959-1977 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Roth, Philip, 1996-2000 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Rubinstein, Annette, 1959, 1975, 1993-2000, undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Sacco, Nicola and Bartolomeo Vanzetti, 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Salomon, Haym, 1971-1977, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Salomon, Haym: Notes and Research Material, 1973, undated (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Salomon, Haym: Notes and Research Material, undated (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Salzman, Neil, 1987-1988 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - 'Sanctuary': Treatment of Central American Refugees, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Saperstein, David, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Sarna, Jonathan, 1979-1996 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1947-1987 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Schulman, Jay, 1986-1987 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Secularism, 1957-1984, 1990-1993 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Seeger, Pete, 1978-2001 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Seldes, George, 1982, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Seliger, Ralph, 1996-1997 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Seligman Affair, 1877: Joseph Seligman, Henry Ward Beecher (Research), 1943, 1947, undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Shadow of Heroes (Hungarian Uprising), 1961-1962 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Shaftel, Oscar, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Shalom Coalition, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Shankman, Arnold, 1973-1983 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Shatzky, Joel, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Shire, Amy, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Shoah, Film, 1985-1987 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Sholom Aleichem Memorial Foundation, 1995-1999 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Siegman, Henry, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Singer, Isaac Bashevis, 1966-1998 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Sipser, Philip, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Slavery, 1963-1977, undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Sleeper, Jim, 1986-1994 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Slomovitz, Philip, 1987-1993 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Social Justice, 1922-1957, undated (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Socialism, 1938, 1974-1989, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Socialist Movement - Early: Attitude of Jewish Press (Including Henryk Erlich and Victor Alter), 1930-1957, undated (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Socialist Press, 1945-1954, undated (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Sokolow, Anna, 1941, 1943, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - "Some Attitudes of the East European Jewish Immigrants toward Organized Jewish Charity in the U.S., 1890-1900," Silver, Harold: Excerpts from Masters' Thesis, 1934 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Soviet Dissidents, 1972-1985 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Soviet Emigres, 1974, 1985-1991 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Spanish Civil War Veterans, 1976-2002 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Spanish Civil War Veterans: City College Scholarship and Memorial, 1975-1980, undated (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Spanish Civil War Veterans: City College Scholarship and Memorial - "A Letter of Remembrance to Wilfred Mendelson, '35", 1980 (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Spirituality, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Stalin Revisionists: "Cleaning Up Stalin's Act" by Adam Hochschild, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - Statue of Liberty (I), 1981-1991 (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - Statue of Liberty (II), 1981-1991 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - Stavis, Morton, 1983, 1992-1993 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Strauss, Robert S., 1979 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Streisand, Barbra, 1975, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Struggle Against Fascism in Germany (fragment of translation by G.S.), undated; 2014.051 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Suhl, Yuri, 1955, 1986-1993 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - "Theory of History": Various Notes and Articles, 1946-1953 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Timerman, Jacobo, 1981, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Tito, Josip Broz, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Toynbee, Arnold and Jewish History, 1948-1961 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Tricentennial of Jews in America (Articles from Brazil and Argentina), 1954 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Trumbo, Dalton: The Devil in the Book, 1956 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Twain, Mark and the Soviet Union, 1948, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Twenty-first Century: End of Millenium Plan (Humorous), 1989 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Ukranians and Jews, 1983-1991 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - United Hebrew Trades, 1948-1975 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - United Hebrew Trades, 1986-1989, undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - United Hebrew Trades: "The Political Origins of the United Hebrew Trades, 1888" - Typescripts / Drafts (I), [1948], 1978, undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - United Hebrew Trades: "The Political Origins of the United Hebrew Trades, 1888" - Typescripts / Drafts (II), [1948], 1978, undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - United Hebrew Trades: Research Notes, 1940-1950, undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - United Hebrew Trades: Research Notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - United Jewish War Effort / Jewish Trade Union Committee for Tanks and Bombers for the Red Army: Stephen S. Wise, Max Perlow, Morris Muster, Alex Bittelman, 1942-1945 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - United States Census, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - United States Economy, 1973-1986 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Van Doren, Mark, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Vanunu Case (Mordechai Vanunu), 1987-2000 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Vetch, M.: Various Articles, 1934-1935 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Vietnam, 1966, 1973-1983 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Wald, Alan, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Wald, Lillian D., 1971 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Resistance, 1942-1957, undated (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Resistance: "The Wall" (Reviews), 1950 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Uprising - 50th Anniversary, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Waskow, Arthur, 1985-1989 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Watergate, 1973-1987 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - We Accuse! The Story of the Miscarriage of American Justice in the Case of J. Robert Oppenheimer, Joseph and Stewart Alsop, 1954, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Weber, Lillian, [1994] (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Wellstone, Paul, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - West, Cornel, 1991-1993 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1974-1997 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Wine, Sherwin (Secularism / Humanism), 1981-1984 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Wine, Sherwin (Secularism / Humanism), 1985-1990 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - Wisse, Ruth, 1991-1993 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Women's Issues, 1952-1982 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Women's Issues, 1984-2001, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1947-1954 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Workmen's Circle, 1956-1996, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Workmen's Circle: Proceedings of 50th Jubilee Convention, 1950 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - World War II, 1938-1946, 1963-1994 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - World War II: 50th Anniversary, 1988-1990, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Wright, Richard, 1977-1995 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Yaffe, Richard, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Yiddish Language, 1934, 1943-2000 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Yiddish Press, 1932-1971 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, 1973-1977, 1993-2000 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Yugoslavia, 1992-1994 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Yugoslavia, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Yugoslavia, 1996, undated (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Yugoslavia: Publications, 1948-1950 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Zedek: Newsletter of the Social Activist Professors Defense Foundation, 1981-1986 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Zhitlowsky, Chaim, 1945, 1969-1975 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Zhitlowsky, Chaim, 1976-1984 (Box 42, Folder 20)
- Series V: Audio-Visual Material, 1953-2000
  The final series is a group of audio cassettes and reel-to-reel tapes and one VHS cassette. Of particular interest are nine interviews with Morris Schappes. Also included are a number of WBAI broadcasts on various topics including The Merchant of Venice, "Women and Orthodoxy," and Jews and the Black Panthers. Jewish Currents-sponsored events include luncheon speeches, awards presentations and several forums and discussions. On the video cassette, Nancy Savin discusses Emma Lazarus with Schappes.
  Materials are arranged chronologically within each subseries.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements Note
  Due to the fragile nature of much of the original media, items in this series must have digital surrogates made before they can be used by researchers. Requests should be sent to tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu. (Note that surrogates are available for several of the interviews.)
  - Subseries VA: Audio Cassettes
    - "Human Beings Fused Together," Sponsored by Concerned Citizens, [Jan 1973] (Box 43, Cassette 1)
    - Interview: Schappes at the Immigration Museum, Feb 1975 (Box 43, Cassette 2)
      General Note
      For Researcher Use: CDs 68 (Cassette 2/A) and 69 (Cassette 2/B)
    - Kapelye Audition Tape: Henry Sapoznik, 1980 (Box 43, Cassette 3)
    - The Merchant of Venice Discussion (WNET, Channel 13), Feb 23, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 4)
    - Allen, Charles [Sholom Aleichem Club]: "Resurgent Right", Mar 14, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 5)
    - Schappes at WBAI: The Merchant of Venice (1 and 2), Apr 6, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 6)
    - Schappes at WBAI: The Merchant of Venice (3 and 4), Apr 6, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 7)
    - Schappes at WBAI: The Merchant of Venice (5), Apr 6, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 8)
    - Schappes at WBAI: Shylock and Censorship (3 and 4), Apr 6, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 9)
    - Jewish Currents at WBAI: Isabel Pearlman, Max Rosenfeld and Dennis Marden Theatre Ensemble, Apr 10, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 10)
    - Schneyer at WBAI, May 4, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 11)
    - WBAI: Side A - Rubenstein, Annette and Morton Stavis re: PLO, May 18, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 12)
    - WBAI: Side B - L'ag B'omer, Schappes re CCNY, May 22, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 12)
    - Jewish Currents Presents Emma Lazarus, Jun 29, 1981 (Box 43, Cassette 13)
    - Townsend Harris Lunch @ Vista Hotel (with Schappes), May 23, 1982 (Box 43, Cassette 14)
    - Socialist Scholars Conference: Black-Jewish Relations - Major Owens, Bill Tatum, Ruth Messinger and Schappes, Apr 19, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 15)
    - Sanctuary: Andre Gottfruend - [American Jewish Congress], Sep 19, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 16)
    - Emma Lazarus Living History Tribute: Goldstein, Judy - Jewish Community Council Delegate Assembly, Oct 22, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 17)
    - Emma Lazarus Living History Tribute: Goldstein, Judy - Jewish Community Council Delegate Assembly, Oct 22, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 18)
    - Great Peace March: Jewish Currents Office - Paul Ziegler, Jerry Eisner, David Hacker and Schappes, Oct 24, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 19)
    - Rosenfeld, Frayde, Nov 23, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 20)
    - "Happy Hanukkah, My Friend" (The Hanukkah Song): A Holiday Musical Greeting, 1986 (Box 43, Cassette 21)
    - Educating Immigrants: Schappes, CCNY, Apr 28, 1987 (Box 43, Cassette 22)
    - Jews and the Constitution: Schappes, Aug 2, 1987 (Box 43, Cassette 23)
    - "from Alvena Seckar", Jan 25, 1988 (Box 43, Cassette 24)
    - Jewish Currents: Jackson, Apr 9, 1988 (Box 43, Cassette 25)
    - Jewish Currents Forum: Sid Resnick; Paul Robeson, Jr., Jan 28, 1990 (Box 43, Cassette 26)
    - Sandler, Boris: Taped Live at 23rd St. Y, Apr 21, 1990 (Box 43, Cassette 27)
    - Arnoni Award: Schappes to Platt, Jewish Currents Luncheon, May 5, 1991 (Box 43, Cassette 28)
    - Interview: Schappes at WBAI, Jan 13, 1992 (Box 43, Cassette 29)
    - "from Ariel Wiener", Jan 18, 1992 (Box 43, Cassette 30)
    - Luncheon, Mar 3, 1992 (Box 43, Cassette 31)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Stan Rosen, University of Illinois (1,5), May 5, 1992 (Box 43, Cassette 32)
      General
      For Researcher Use: CDs 70 (Cassette 32/A) and 71 (Cassette 32/B)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Stan Rosen, University of Illinois (2,3), May 5, 1992 (Box 43, Cassette 33)
      For Researcher Use: CDs 72 (Cassette 33/A) and 73 (Cassette 33/B)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Stan Rosen, University of Illinois (4), May 5, 1992 (Box 43, Cassette 34)
      For Researcher Use: CD 74 (Cassette 34/B)
    - Jewish Currents Concert: Schappes, Nov 7, 1993 (Box 43, Cassette 35)
    - Jewish Currents: [Ruth Rubin], Dec 7, 1994 (Box 43, Cassette 36)
    - US Holocaust Memorial Museum: Witnesses to the Holocaust, 1994 (Box 43, Cassette 37)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Gail Malmgreen (Tape 1), Oct 11, 1996 (Box 43, Cassette 38)
      For Researcher Use: CDs 75 (Cassette 38/A) and 76 (Cassette 38/B)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Gail Malmgreen (Tape 2), Oct 11, 1996 (Box 43, Cassette 39)
      For Researcher Use: CDs 77 (Cassette 39/A) and 78 (Cassette 39/B)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Joanna Morse, Mar 7, 1997 (Box 43, Cassette 40)
    - "Women and Orthodoxy": WBAI, Beyond the Pale: The Progressive Jewish Radio Hour, Mar 19, 1997 (Box 43, Cassette 41)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon: Tape 1 - Ruth Messinger, Itche Goldberg, Joe Murphy, Henry Foner and Gerald Stillman, May 4, 1997 (Box 43, Cassette 42)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon: Tape 2 - Gerald Stillman (cont'd), Schappes, May 4 1997 (Box 43, Cassette 43)
    - Schappes and Fergus Bordevich, May 9, 1997 (Box 43, Cassette 44)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon: Speech - Mark Rosenblum, May 3, 1998 (Box 43, Cassette 45)
    - Interview: Schappes- by Lauren Strauss, Nov 11, 1999 (Box 43, Cassette 46)
      Transcript - Box 4, Folder 24
    - Borscht Circuit: Comic and Serious (from Alvena Seckar), May 24, 2000 (Box 43, Cassette 47)
    - Jews in Soviet Union: Intro and cont'd, undated (Box 43, Cassette 48)
    - Jews in Soviet Union: 3 and "end of workshop", undated (Box 43, Cassette 49)
    - Schappes (Side A); Gidon Pajenson (Side B), undated (Box 43, Cassette 50)
    - Interview: Schappes - Leonard Lehrman, Tape 1, undated (Box 43, Cassette 51)
    - Interview: Schappes - Leonard Lehrman, Tape 2, undated (Box 43, Cassette 52)
    - "Walden on Katz on Harap", undated (Box 43, Cassette 53)
    - Miracle at Philadelphia (Side A); Emma's Walk, The Path of Liberty (Side B), undated (Box 43, Cassette 54)
  - Subseries VB: Reel-to-Reel Tapes
    - WBAI: East Side, East Side: A Museum View - Schappes, Oct 17, 1966 (Box 43, Reel 55)
      Transcript - Box 18, Folder 20
    - WBAI: Commentary on Jewish Affairs (Israel Confronts in U.N. Series) - Schappes, Oct 25, 1966 (Box 43, Reel 56)
      Transcript - Box 18, Folders 21 and 22
    - WBAI: Two More Jewish Nobel Prize Winners in Literature - Schappes, Nov 1, 1966 (Box 43, Reel 57)
      Transcript - Box 18, Folders 23 and 24
    - WBAI: Security Council Evades Syrian-Israel Crisis - Schappes, Nov 9, 1966 (Box 43, Reel 58)
      Transcript - Box 18, Folder 25
    - WBAI: Black Power and the Jews - Schappes, Nov 16, 1966 (Box 43, Reel 59)
      Transcript - Box 18, Folder 26
    - WBAI: The Anti-Semitic Blood Libel in Fact and Fiction - Schappes, Nov 24, 1966 (Box 43, Reel 60)
      Transcript - Box 18, Folder 27 and Box 19, Folder 1
    - KPFK: Soviet Press Review: Mandel, William on Anti-Semitism in the Soviet Union, Mar 10, 1969 (Box 43, Reel 61)
    - WBAI: Jewish Liberation Project, The Jews and the Black Panthers, Sep 11, 1970 (Box 43, Reel 62)
    - Radical Jewish Youth Look at Israel Reel 1 of 2, Jan 31, 1971 (Box 43, Reel 63)
    - Radical Jewish Youth Look at Israel Reel 2 of 2, Jan 31, 1971 (Box 43, Reel 64)
    - Barry Farber Show: Schappes, undated (Box 43, Reel 65)
    - Reel 3: Israel and Syria; Israel and the UN; Black Power; Anti-Semitic Blood Libel, undated (Box 43, Reel 66)
  - Subseries VC: Video Cassette (VHS)
    - Interview: Schappes - by Nancy Savin (re: Emma Lazarus), Nov 6, 1977 (Box 43, Cassette 67)
  - Subseries VD: Audio Cassettes Addendum
    - "Communism, Anti-Christ and Fatima" by Wallace Johnson, Part 1, 1978 (Box 44, Cassette 79)
    - "Communism, Anti-Christ and Fatima" by Wallace Johnson, Part 2, 1978 (Box 44, Cassette 80)
    - "The Impossible Dream" Irene Paull Memorial Ceremony, Oct 11, 1981 (Box 44, Cassette 81)
    - Freyda Rosenfeld Interview, Nov 23, 1986 (Box 44, Cassette 82)
    - Interview: Schappes by Eric Gordon for NJA, Jun 29, 1987 (Box 44, Cassette 83)
    - Yiddish Books on Tape: Holiday Tales by Sholem Aleichem, 1987 (Box 44, Cassette 84)
    - Lecha Dodi, 1988 (Box 44, Cassette 85)
    - Vorspan/Annual Jewish Currents Dinner, May 7, 1989 (Box 44, Cassette 86)
    - Interview: Schappes by Eric Gordon for NJA, Jul 1989 (Box 44, Cassette 87)
    - Catholic Newswire Issue 1, Nov 1989 (Box 44, Cassette 88)
    - "Skinheads in the Soviet Union/Hertzberg Exalts Rabbinic Elitism", Dec 26, 1989 (Box 44, Cassette 89)
    - Chosen Voices by Mark Slobin, 1989 (Box 44, Cassette 90)
    - Jewish Currents Forum Taped by Morris Willdorf, Jan 28, 1990 (Box 44, Cassette 91)
    - Jewish Currents Part 1, Jan 28, 1990 (Box 44, Cassette 92)
    - Jewish Currents Parts 3 and 4, Jan 28, 1990 (Box 44, Cassette 93)
    - Jewish Currents Parts 3 and 4, Jan 28, 1990 (Box 44, Cassette 94)
    - Sholeim Aleichem 75th Yartzeit Yivo, Apr 21, 1991 (Box 44, Cassette 95)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon: Rabbi Marshall T. Meyer, May 5, 1991 (Box 44, Cassette 96)
    - Morris U. Schappes Meeting with Pinovick, Oct 27, 1991 (Box 44, Cassette 97)
    - Judy Frankel Spehardic Songs of Love and Hope, 1992 (Box 44, Cassette 98)
    - Morris U. Schappes Interview with Andrea Raab, Feb 14, 1993 (Box 44, Cassette 99)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon, May 5, 1996 (Box 44, Cassette 100)
    - Interview: Schappes on Emma Lazarus by Nan Rubin for WBAI, Oct 7, 1999 (Box 44, Cassette 101)
    - Daniel Levinson Hebrew/Yiddish, undated (Box 44, Cassette 102)
    - Jewish Currents, undated (Box 44, Cassette 103)
    - Jewish Currents /Jackson, undated (Box 44, Cassette 104)
    - "Shaking of Ethnic Bonds": Colm Green, undated (Box 44, Cassette 105)
  - Subseries VE: Reel-to-Reel Tapes Addendum
    - Mr Louis Harap Jewish Life, 1953 (Box 44, Reel 106)
    - WMIE "Emma Lazarus/Mollie [Olsen}", 1958 (Box 44, Reel 107)
    - Jewish Currents Panel Discussion: "Image of the Jew in the Negro Community", Nov 11, 1962 (Box 44, Reel 108)
    - "Twenty-Three Years Later" Morris U. Schappes Interview with Vladka Meed, 1966 (Box 44, Reel 109)
    - WOR-FM "8-9AM 2/1/1970" and "Happy Birthday Jesus", Dec 24, 1969-Feb 1, 1970 (Box 44, Reel 110)
    - "Concentration Camps, The Jews & Resistance", Feb 2, 1970 (Box 44, Reel 111)
    - Morris U. Schappes at Emma Lazarus J. Womens Club Convention on the Destruction of the I.W.O., Feb 11, 1970 (Box 44, Reel 112)
    - Jewish Currents Conference, Feb 14, 1970 (Box 44, Reel 113)
    - Jewish Currents Working Conference, Jan 31, 1970 (Box 44, Reel 114)
    - "Dr. Earle Reynolds Professor at Hiroshima Women's College and Skipper of Yacht Phoenix, which Sailed the Bikini Atol Test Zone in 1958", undated (Box 44, Reel 115)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon Part 1, undated (Box 44, Reel 116)
    - Jewish Currents Luncheon Part 2, undated (Box 44, Reel 117)
    - Joe Dolan Interview of Mildred Simon, undated (Box 44, Reel 118)
    - Lecture in Yiddish, undated (Box 44, Reel 119)
    - Morris U. Schappes: Czechoslovokia, undated (Box 44, Reel 120)